Cristian Salas

Boston, MA | cristianrodriquezsalas@gmail.com | 347-447-2583

OBJECTIVE STATEMENT

I believe in providing users with a comfortable experience, recognizing its potential for significant impact. My track record includes creating features that boosted customer retention by over 60%, which incentivised partnerships with new stakeholder companies. My goal is to work with companies to develop software solutions that address complex challenges and deliver substantial impacts across diverse customer demographics.

SKILLS

- Language: Javascript, Java, Python, C, C++, SQL, Kotlin, HTML, CSS
- Libraries/Frameworks: .NET, DynamoDB, Azure, AWS, React, React Native, Typescript, MongoDB, Node.js, Jest, Jenkins
- Other: Figma, Adobe Creative Cloud, Git/Github/GitLab, Linux, Obsidian

WORK EXPERIENCE

BitSight Technologies

Boston, MA

Frontend Software Engineer

Jun 2021-March 2023

- Owned, and implemented full stack React projects of web services and REST API's for Glass-Lewis Report and BitSight Badge, improving the UX for ~150M users.
- Handled large data to produce reports for client ransomware/breach assessments, adhering strictly to industry best practices, contributing to product enhancement, increasing client retention by 60%.
- Lead and collaborated closely across several development and design teams to improve and fix React legacy code, improving Executive Report and Security Ratings user experience across ~ 100,000 companies.
- Designed and built AWS cloud-scale infrastructure components for new Content Delivery Network, increasing global distribution for web features, and reducing error rates to less than 1%.
- Developed, and maintained BitSight's resilient CyberSecurity Rating Data Distribution system, ensuring fault-tolerance and accuracy of data availability, resulting in a 0.1% data corruption rate.
- Demonstrated strong problem-solving skills by solving and improving clean, and reliable testable code, replacing over 80% of legacy code, as well as created documentation to help improve developers' code quality across SWE teams.
- Collaborated with developer, business, and design teams in an Agile environment to deliver on-demand software solutions that meet 100% of the requirements set by stakeholders.
- Engaged in regular professional development teams, hosting FrontEnd Forums for learning and presenting new technologies across teams, resulting in a 30% increase in the adoption of innovative solutions across projects.

Hack.Diversity Boston, MA

Software Engineer

Jan 2021-Sep 2021

- Designed, prototype, and visualized ~1M data sets on website by using Figma, and fullstack MERN framework.
- Collaborated with fullstack teams to connect front-end with back-end features with flexible interfaces to allow users to visualize data.

Decibel TherapeuticsBoston, MA

Software Engineer

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

- Improved MongoDB database, Python and React legacy code, which increase associates' productivity by 30%.
- Executed large-scale web scraping large scales for ~10,000 of medical journals from sources daily and uploaded to AWS.
- Created complete Python library for tasks such as supervise, test, clean, automate, filter, and facilitate the manipulation of ~10,000 medical journals and scientific entries.

LEADERSHIP

Hack.Diversity

Boston, MA

Software Engineer Mentor

Sept 2021-Present

 Mentored junior developers and actively shared insights to accelerate their growth, and aiding to connect their network, contributing to developing strong teams.

EDUCATION

Suffolk University College of Art and Science

Boston, MA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Minor in Graphic Design (GPA: 3.5)

May 2021

Awards: Christian Herter Scholarship Award 2015 Recipient, Google Cybersecurity Certificate 2023